# Lawrence Cousino

https://github.com/lcousino

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lcousino/

http://www.larrycousino.com

CELL (419) 699-0624 • E-MAIL lawrence.cousino@gmail.com

Fredericksburg, Virginia 22406

Creative, engaging and determined, full stack developer with a passion for front-end development and UI Design. My experience has taught me to focus on customer satisfaction through teamwork, while maintaining a commitment to exceed expectations. Actively pursuing opportunities to provide programming skills, leadership, and enthusiasm to a fast-paced environment as a full stack developer. As a 21-year United States Air Force Veteran, I am a proven leader and dedicated team player, who can make decisions, works well under pressure and improvise on the fly!

OVILLO

#### **SKILLS**

### <Backend>

Java | Spring Boot | Thymeleaf | MySQL | NoSQL (Mongo) | AJAX | AWS | NGINX

### <Frontend>

TypeScript | Angular8 | Bootstrap | Cordova | Ionic | jQuery | HTML | CSS | JS

#### <Other Skills>

Agile Project Management | Agile Methodologies | Scrum methodologies | Repository Pattern | UX/UI | Adobe Photoshop | Microsoft 365 Suite End-User/Administration | troubleshooting with Mac OSX and Windows | Leadership | Event Management | Collaboration | SQL Server | Windows 7, 10 | SharePoint 2013, 365 | Microsoft Project | Microsoft Visio | Smartsheets | TCP/IP | DNS | DHCP | Meraki Full-Stack | Mitel 5000 VOIP Phone System | Windstream My Office Suite Phone System | Jive PBX | SD-WAN

#### **EDUCATION**

Southern Careers Institute Powered by Woz U Full Stack Web Developer Certification

**Graduated March 2020** 

**ECPI University - Richmond, Virginia** 

**Graduated Sep. 2012** 

B. S. Computer and Information Science, Network Security

**PROJECTS** 

Everyday People Discussion Board/ Group Project <a href="https://github.com/Woz-U-Group-Projects/mythical-techies">https://github.com/Woz-U-Group-Projects/mythical-techies</a>

The purpose of the project was to be able to freely post information in multiple subject areas that allowed interaction between users. A good place to ask for and receive information from others in this social platform?

- Backend: Java Spring Boot, JPA
- Database: MySql
- Frontend: Angular, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Independent IT Contractor, Self-Employed

Dec. 2019 - Present

- Project manager for client 80+ phone system replacement; ensured deadlines met; oversaw communication between vendor and client, leading to successful execution on established date
- Onsite coordinator during move from workgroup to domain environment; replaced forty outdated phones for customer facing offices; provided smooth transition for users moving new domain
- Oversees ongoing phishing education and training program; provides valuable client penetration testing with realistic customized emails; decrease in phished users and increase of awareness
- Provides remote support for >300 end-users and >220 nodes; tirelessly strives for quality care

# **Lawrence Cousino**

### **IT Manager, Huber Motor Cars**

Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2019

- Oversaw move to cloud based My Office Suite VOIP phone system and implementations of SD-WAN; improved aging phone system with modern cloud-based PBX with system uptime of 99%
- Led transition of Microsoft Office 2010 to Office 365; proved support, administration and training
- Authored 3-yr hardware replacement plan; ensures brand compliance met or exceeded

### **Senior IT Specialist, Huber Motor Cars**

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2016

- Prepared and configured six servers with Server 2012 R2 for deployment within the organization
- Researched and managed phone system music on hold feature; \$3,200 annual savings
- Authored numerous group policies automating printers, standardized desktop wallpaper, password policy and other needed organization policies ensuring consistency and compliance

## **Desktop Support Lead, Rosner Automotive Group**

Apr. 2014 - Sep. 2015

- Oversaw day-to-day department operations due to CIO working remotely out-of-state; excelled in management and lauded for departments superb customer service standards
- Designed company's first ever desktop wallpaper; highlighting organization and brands
- Designated as SharePoint administrator and designer; responsible for the look and content of the primary Intranet site and subsites; trained end-users and assisted in movement of content